Sarah G. Evans

404-918-8152 | Email | GitHub | Medium | LinkedIn | Personal Site

1

Self-motivated full stack web developer with a passion for deep knowledge. Experience in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript, React, and Redux, with a background in functional MUMPS-based programming. Proven ability to master new technologies and solve difficult problems with strong skills in team-building and management. Once learned an unfamiliar coding language with only a binder of handwritten notes as a teaching tool!

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Equidestined - GitHub | App

The best way to find new places to meet your friends in the middle.

- + Built models, forms, and action controllers in Ruby on Rails.
- + Configured Geocoder gem to convert between addresses and latitude/longitude.
- + Designed the PostgreSQL database schema and configured Active Record associations.
- + Created a custom Rails module for OAuth authentication with Google Maps and Yelp APIs.

Pixel Playground - GitHub | App

A collaborative art experience inspired by Reddit's Rplace.

- + Rendered the drawing surface using HTML5 Canvas and JavaScript.
- + Used Action Cable to implement WebSockets for chat and real-time canvas updates.
- + Coded back-end APIs using Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL.
- + Built front end in Javascript with JQuery and styled with Materialize and custom CSS.

Story Board - GitHub - Front End | GitHub - Back End | Demo

A work in progress that allows writers to storyboard by noting and rearranging their scenes.

- + Built and designed front end using JavaScript, React, Redux, and custom CSS.
- + Coded back-end APIs using Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL.
- + Implemented React-Draggable node module to allow drag and drop for scenes.
- + Managed user authentication using JWT tokens.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript | Ruby | Rails | SQL | React | Redux | MUMPS

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

latric Systems, Boxford, MA

Technical Services Support Programmer, *December 2011 - February 2017*

- + Provided advanced-level technical support for cloud-based and enterprise healthcare applications.
- + Troubleshot and resolved mission-critical issues with code, applications, and servers.
- + Ensured that 100% of personal client roster met attestation deadlines for Meaningful Use software.
- + Participated in design, development, testing, and support for multiple applications.

MEDITECH, Atlanta, GA

Supervisor, InSync Financial Service Programmers, October 2008 - December 2011

Senior Developer and Support Programmer, April 2005 - October 2008

- + Managed and mentored a small team of support and development programmers.
- + Prioritized development tasks with an emphasis on meeting all product and client deadlines.
- + Oversaw group code review process to ensure consistent quality of releases.
- + Developed custom software solutions and resolved escalated client issues.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School - 2017

+ Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript online program

Georgia State University - Atlanta, GA - 2003 - 2006

+ Undergraduate Coursework: Computer Science

Emory University - Atlanta, GA - 1998

+ Bachelor of Arts: Psychology